This is an AI generated photo of me.
I've never been to this gas station.
I've never worn this jacket, and I've
never even held this dollar bill. The AI
model that made this, GPT Image 2, just
dropped earlier this week and is already
crushing every benchmark and is sitting
on top of the LM Arena leaderboard,
which is basically the most recognized
AI image model ranking. But, here's the
thing that nobody talks about. When it
comes to AI UGC, the part that actually
makes money for people with AI, does it
hold up to the current leader, which is
Nano Banana? So, I had to put them
head-to-head on seven different tests.
Now, these will be mostly focused on
UGC, but the tests will translate over
to other categories as well. So, even if
you're not creating UGC content with AI,
you can still watch this and it will be
useful for you. All right, let's get
into it, and I hope you enjoy. Before we
start, I will say that I'll be testing
GPT Image 2, Nano Banana 2, but also
Nano Banana Pro, since in my experience
and working with AI UGC, Nano Banana Pro
has been providing the best results up
until today. So, we'll see if GPT Image
2 beats it or not. Starting off with the
first test, it is going to be organic
phone selfies. And here as you can see,
I have written out a very simple prompt
describing a selfie of a girl holding a
Starbucks coffee. Throughout this entire
test, I'll be using the same prompt on
every model so we can get very clear
results on which one performs best. And
these are the results that we got for
this prompt. And right away, we can see
the weakest model when it comes to
realistic organic phone selfies is Nano
Banana 2. We can rule it out completely.
There's no competition.
Now, with GPT Image 2 and Nano Banana
Pro, these are actually pretty close
results. I do notice that Nano Banana
Pro ignored the selfie style and the
character is using both hands to hold
the object, but in terms of quality,
it's actually hard to choose which one
of these two is best. I do notice that
the GPT 2 generation looks a bit more
flat and does also looks a bit more
organic, like it was taken on an actual
phone. But, Nano Banana Pro doesn't look
like it was taken on a professional
camera either. It has that very organic
phone-looking camera style. Now, before
I give my ranking on which one of these
two is actually better, I would like to
cover it that the GPT Image 2 gives you
the option to select quality settings.
Starting from low to mid to high. Each
of these tiers have different prices.
The low starts at half a credit on Higgs
Field, the mid starts at two credits,
and the high quality tier starts at four
credits. So, the high quality is eight
times as expensive as the low one. Do
you see the difference between these
three? Probably not from a distance, but
if we go in further and zoom in, that's
where the quality really starts
appearing. For example here, I zoomed in
on the hair, and that's where we can
start to see the details disappear. It
just looks very unorganic and almost
like it's warping. On the high quality,
we can see that there's no artifacts of
such. Even the thing at which the GPT
Image 2 model is weak at, it creates
like these kind of dots all over the
place once there is a more complex
texture, the high quality model seems to
get rid of that, and that's only a
problem with the low quality one. But,
is it worth it to spend eight times as
many credits on the same picture that
you can only see the difference once you
zoom in? Probably not. So, I think
overall, the best option to go with is
the mid quality. The price is only two
credits per a single generation. The mid
quality generation is probably the best
in price to value. So, I would most
likely go with that. Now, if we have to
decide a winner between GPT Image 2 and
Nano Banana Pro here, it's kind of hard
to pick the winner since the quality is
essentially the same. The only thing is
that Nano Banana Pro is a slightly bit
cheaper. So, I'll give the first round
win to Nano Banana Pro.
Moving on to the second
test, which is character consistency.
This is probably the most important
aspect if you're creating AI UGC videos
or AI influencers is the consistency of
the characters. So, every generation
must look exactly like them without any
small little weird changes. Together
with the character consistency, I also
decided to include three other reference
photos for certain objects that the
character has to hold, the background,
and the outfit as well. This way, I can
really test out how good the models are
at following orders and fulfilling every
little smallest detail in the
generations. Here are the results.
From first glance, we can already see
that GPT Image 2 performed the best with
character consistency cuz that actually
looks like me. The other photos kind of
resemble me, but if we look at the
reference photo, it looks like a
completely different version of me. As
an actual selfie image, the Nano Banana
generations actually look decent.
There's nothing that looks extremely
fake and it's just a very well overall
composed shot. I do notice that it has
that slight warm yellow tone to it,
which for some reason it cannot seem to
get rid of. But, apart from the
character consistency, it did everything
correct. But, comparing these two to GPT
Image 2, this looks way better. It did
create this weird shadow on my face
coming from the dollar bill, almost like
someone shining a light from the side,
which is not something that I asked for,
and it doesn't look like regular selfie
lighting. So, I had to rerun the prompt
just to see it once more. And yeah, here
we have the clear defined answer. GPT
Image 2 is just better with character
consistency. Both models seem to be very
good at executing the rest of the tasks,
like the background, the outfit. One
little mess up here for the GPT Image 2
is this part of the jacket. So, it
doesn't have the letter on that side of
the zipper. So, if you're creating ads
for your clothing brand, let's say, make
sure to pay close attention to things of
that nature. Overall, in this round, GPT
Image 2 is declared winner. Now, moving
on to the next test, that will be
talking head UGC. This will not be a
regular selfie photo of me like the
previous generations. The talking head
UGC generation like this will be used
for something like a start frame to a
video. So, it's really important to nail
down the character consistency once
again, but it's also very important to
make it look like a screenshot of a
video that someone recorded on their
phone holding it right in front of them.
You can pause the video if you want to
read the prompt, but basically, I just
added a lot of detail for how the
talking head UGC generation should look.
Now, let's see the results.
I'm not sure if Nano Banana got
nerfed for some reason while generating
this, but it added this hand, which
makes absolutely no sense. Also, it
completely ignored the part of the
prompt which said no phone in frame and
still added it right here. The angle
looks nothing like a real UGC video
would look. I'm sure if you tweak the
prompt the right way that you can
actually get a good result with Nano
Banana Pro as well, but yeah, I mean,
GPT Image 2 just seems to read between
the lines of the prompt and understand
what it is that you want. It doesn't
necessarily have to have perfect
instructions from you to get the best
results. Same thing from previous
generations, the character consistency
is just not it on these two generations.
I also wanted to test out how it would
generate a frame from a video where the
person is
holding the phone and walking.
So, let's see
the results. And once again, the
character looks nothing like the
reference photo. Also, Nano Banana likes
to use this weird clothing that no one
wears in real life. So, unless you
specify what the outfit should look
like, it's going to give you this weird
texture shirt, which
doesn't look good. Now, GPT Image 2
character is consistent once again. The
generation looks low quality, like a
screenshot from a video would. Also, I
cannot complain about the quality of
Nano Banana Pro. You can see that the
background is in motion blur. Nothing
looks weird. So, in that sense, these
models are equal, but in talking head
UGC, GPT Image 2 wins once again. Moving
on to the next test, it will be a
product in hand generation. I took a
random skin care product from Pinterest
and used that as the reference photo.
And for the prompt, I just specified it
to look like a real phone camera photo
with the flashlight enabled. Let's see
the results.
From first glance, they actually all
look very solid. There is nothing that
any of them fall short on at first
glance. All of them have different
lighting, so it's hard to compare them
in that regard, but visually, I like the
Nano Pro generation the best with GPT
Image 2 coming in second. But, the
difference here is in the details. So,
as you may have heard that GPT Image 2
is actually the best model when it comes
to text rendering, and this is
absolutely true. If we zoom in on the
GPT Image 2 photo, we can see that all
of the text, no matter what language, is
always executed perfectly. None of the
words are misspelled. The font is always
consistent, and it looks exactly like
the reference photo. On the surface, the
Nano Banana generations also look like
they executed the text perfectly, but if
we zoom in on the smaller text, that's
where we start to see problems. For
example here, Nano Banana 2 spelled this
word as "oity" instead of "oily", and
you can see a couple other examples here
where the Nano Banana models mess up or
misspell the text compared to the
reference photo. This is the case
because GPT Image 2 is trained to treat
text as information, not just a visual
element. Well, Nano Banana, instead of
seeing it as information, it sees it as
shapes, as visual elements, and it just
tries to recreate it as closely as
possible without really any logic behind
it. I wanted to test another product in
hand photo, but in a bit of a different
way. So, I took this chocolate packaging
photo and asked the model to create an
image where the packaging is opened and
the chocolate has been bitten into. And
these are the results. And actually
here, I would say Nano Banana performed
better than GPT Image. On the Nano
image, there is no inconsistencies on
the packaging. The opened wrapper looks
more realistic than it does on the GPT
Image 2. And also, if we check the GPT
Image 2, this piece of the chocolate is
missing its writing. So, would GPT Image
2 nail it with the next generation? Most
likely, yeah. And if your product
doesn't have any small detailed writing
on it, I think all three models are
pretty viable options to use. But,
considering that GPT 2 didn't fail in
the text generation, I'll have to give
this test win to GPT. Now, the fifth
test will be a screen POV, and I'll also
be testing out the camera controls. Here
as the reference photo, I have uploaded
a screenshot of my YouTube channel and
in the prompt I asked it to put the
screenshot on a MacBook screen and take
the image with a 0.5 iPhone camera and
to also have the person making the photo
point at the screen.
And here's the result. Clearly both
models understood the objective and
fulfilled it, but the problem with the
Nano Banana 2 one is it did not create
the 0.5 camera effect. And it also looks
way too highly produced like it was
taken on a professional camera. The
GPT-2 image nailed the 0.5 camera look
and just overall looks way more organic
and real. So, whatever it is that you're
trying to display on your screen, GPT
image 2 is the best option to go with.
If you look at the video thumbnails and
also the titles, then all of the text
including the views and everything else
is perfect. The same cannot be said for
Nano, but that's already expected
considering the previous test results.
In this next prompt, I wanted to test
the models are in converting a laptop
image like this into a phone image. So,
it must not only place the screenshot on
the phone screen, but also convert it
into the YouTube UI. And actually both
models managed to do the job correct.
Also, I didn't specify how the phone
should look, so in the GPT image 2
model, it added this phone stand. On the
Nano generation,
the phone is just standing up vertically
somehow. Also, I much more prefer the
angle of the phone here. You can see
that it's slightly tilted and it's not
perfectly facing the camera. Here, it
just looks way too unreal. Another
generation that I just had to do was a
crypto phantom wallet, but this time I
also specified to make sure that the
phone of the screen is slightly cracked
and also there's some dust on it. As
well as the person holding the phone is
wearing a expensive Rolex watch. And
here are the two results. Once again,
the angle looks way more real on GPT
image 2, but if we look closer here in
the Nano generation, the watch is being
worn backwards, which makes no sense.
The little scratches and grease on the
phone looks way better in the GPT image
2. You can also see it in the Nano
generation, but I think it's clear who
the winner here is. So, the point for
screen POV, I'll give this to GPT image
2. And moving on to the sixth test,
and that is going to be screenshots.
Here I have a very simple prompt of a
WhatsApp conversation screenshot from a
doctor telling the receiver to consider
using coffee for weight loss. And here's
the results. Now, this didn't include
any reference photo for how the
screenshot should look, but the Nano 2
generation decided to use an old UI,
which looks completely outdated. While
the GPT image 2 looks like it was taken
today. If we're being specific, the font
on this generation looks just a tiny bit
off from what the actual WhatsApp font
is, but still this image is the clear
winner.
Another test I did is this email
screenshot from the Gmail app. And I
would say it's almost identically the
same result as the previous generation.
This image looks completely outdated,
doesn't look like a recent screenshot at
all.
And the GPT image 2, while it looks
recent, the font looks slightly off. So,
GPT image 2 takes the win for
screenshots. Now, at this point I think
I've covered everything that is
important for AI UGC content generation.
If I missed something, then let me know,
but for the last seventh test, I just
wanted to play around with it and see
what it is capable of.
So, for example here, I asked it this
very simple prompt to create a children
books illustration of a castle split in
half, to include a lot of different
characters all with their purpose and
role. I'm not sure if any of you
remember this, but this was probably my
favorite part of looking at books as a
kid. And the level of detail in the GPT
image 2 generation is just insane. It
has written out different descriptions
here on the side and they all perfectly
match with the exact number as it is
placed on the illustration itself. Even
though I don't have anything specific to
test in this bonus round, it is clear
that the winner of this test
is GPT image 2. So, there you have it.
Let me know if you agree with these
results and if you have found any use
case where GPT image 2 still lags behind
Nano Banana. I do appreciate you for
watching this video all the way through.
If you did enjoy it, then click like and
subscribe. And if you want to learn more
about AI content creation or how we
could use it to market your brand, then
you can reach out to me in the
description. Peace out.